LUCA FURLANETTO

furlanettoluca92@gmail.com | luc-fur.github.io | Italian Nationality | Birthday 10th Sep 1992

Technical Consultant | SaaS Industry Expert

Technical consultant with 5 years of experience in the SaaS industry across Denmark and the USA. Proficient in software implementation, database management, DevOps, and programming in C++ and Python.

I have recently taken courses to strengthen my programming skills and transition to software development. Having concluded my experience in the USA, I am looking to continue my career in Italy.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

AMCS Group | Dec 2019 - June 2024

2yr 11mo as Software Implementation Consultant in Copenhagen, Denmark 8mo as Senior Consultant in Boston, MA 1yr 4mo as Technical Lead in Boston, MA

As a consultant, I implemented OR-based logistics and routing solutions, integrating software into IT infrastructures, troubleshooting issues, evaluating strategies, and managing projects. In October 2022, I relocated to Boston to lead the implementation of Intelligent Optimization products for the North American market.

As a Technical Lead, I oversaw solution architecture for large-scale enterprise projects, ensuring strategic alignment, seamless system integration, and product readiness in collaboration with customer technical teams.

DTU - Technical University of Denmark | Sep 2018 - Dec 2019

1yr 3 mo as Research and Teaching assistant | Copenhagen, Denmark

Data analysis and ML application for problems related to transport demand and traffic safety. I assisted the professors in preparing lectures and supported students in the MSc course Business Analytics.

EDUCATION

2016-2018 | Master's degree, Transport and Logistics Engineering

DTU - Technical University of Denmark | GPA: 8.3/12

Relevant coursework: Programming (C++ and Python), Data Analysis, ML, Operational Management, Operational Research, Optimization and Supply Chain management. Thesis: Prediction model for transportation demand.

2012-2015 | Bachelor's degree, Urban Regional Planning

IUAV University | GPA: 101/110

Relevant coursework: Math and statistics, urban planning, Topography, Economics and Environmental science.

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Product Owner – Scrum.org Azure fundamentals – Microsoft Prince2 Foundation – Axelos Python backend developer bootcamp - NuCamp

LANGUAGES SPOKEN

Italian – Native English – Fluent